

MILA DECKER

Orlando Based Developer

MILACDECKER@GMAIL.COM | 240-422-1732

LINKED IN: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mila-decker/

GITHUB: https://github.com/deckiedevs PORTFOLIO: https://deckiedevs.github.io

SUMMARY

Web developer with a strong background in science and mathematics that lends itself to an aptitude for programming and troubleshooting. Skilled at logic and reasoning demonstrated by a decade of working in forensic science. Experienced with managing high work volumes and pressing deadlines, proven by successfully eliminating a backlog of over 1,000 firearms cases.

SKILLS

Node.js, Express.js, React, MongoDB, Mongoose, MySQL, Sequelize, JavaScript, JQuery, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Materialize, AJAX, REST API, Git

PROJECTS

Something Special - A Full Stack Group Project

GitHub: https://github.com/deckiedevs/something-special

Deployed Project: https://dd-special.herokuapp.com

- Summary: A community marketplace for listing second-hand event items.
- Roles: Led daily stand-ups, set up back-end architecture, styled web page with BootStrap, and tested and debugged code.
- Tools: Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, Sequelize, Handlebars.js, Bcrypt, FireBase, JavaScript, HTML, BootStrap, CSS, Heroku

What's For Dinner? - A Third-Party API Group Project

GitHub: https://github.com/deckiedevs/whats-for-dinner

Deployed Project: https://deckiedevs.github.io/whats-for-dinner/

- Summary: A recipe finder application utilizing third-party APIs.
- Roles: Managed project deadlines, structured and managed API requests, handled API data rendering, and handled save favorite recipe feature.
- Tools: JavaScript, JQuery, HTML, CSS, Materialize, Math.js, Spoonacular API

Prentus - A Tech Talent Sourcing Network

Live Website: https://prentus.co/

- Summary: A website for finding and risk-free hiring of talent in the tech industry.
- Roles: Built the "Where We Find Undiscovered Talent" section of the homepage to the design specifications of Pretnus founder, Rod Danan.
- Tools: HTML, Bootstrap, Versoly

EXPERIENCE

Forensic Firearms Specialist - Orange County Sheriff's Office, Orlando, FL

NOVEMBER 2017 - PRESENT

- Eliminated a backlog of over 1,000 firearms through efficient time and caseload management.
- Prepare technical reports and perform technical reviews of peer reports.
- Maintain open lines of communication with investigators and prosecutors to deliver the best available forensic evidence for trial.

Crime Scene Investigator II - Orange County Sheriff's Office, Orlando, FL

AUGUST 2013 - NOVEMBER 2017

- Utilized critical thinking and analytical skills to process crime scenes.
- Applied logic, reasoning, and problem solving skills to conduct investigations.
- Explained complex scientific and mathematical concepts through over 600 training hours as a certified Field Training Officer.
- Prepared demonstrative tools for courtroom testimony.

Crime Laboratory Technician II - Baltimore Police Department, Baltimore, MD

JUNE 2011 - AUGUST 2013

- Responded to, evaluated, and processed thousands of crime scenes.
- Prepared reports and diagrams for courtroom testimony.

Academic Resource Center Tutor - University of Baltimore, Baltimore, MD

SEPTEMBER 2008 - MAY 2010

- Tutored peers in algebra, statistics, and criminal justice.
- Organized and led group study sessions.
- Pioneered an online tutoring program that gave students the option to learn remotely.

EDUCATION

University of Central Florida - Full Stack Coding Bootcamp Certificate

OCTOBER 2020 - APRIL 2021, ORLANDO, FL

University of Baltimore- Forensic Science, B.S.

SEPTEMBER 2008 - MAY 2010, BALTIMORE, MD

- Graduated Summa Cum Laude
- Dean's List

Montgomery College - General Studies, A.A./A.S.

SEPTEMBER 2006 - MAY 2008, TAKOMA PARK, MD

- Inducted into the Phi Theta Kappa Honor Society
- Dean's List

REFERENCES

Available upon request.